想在此处添加您的广告信息？立即联系 www.OpenSubtitles.org
翻译:Hunter  李大K  Kurt_Weller  潇风
翻译:不明真相的吃瓜群众  花少念  Rila_Marc  韬光养晦气
校对:Lisafish  ironheart  Akila_K  Kurt_Weller
总校:ironheart  Kurt_Weller
时间轴:Kurt_Weller  冰糖肘子
特效&压制:Kurt_Weller
蓝血字幕组原创译制
追捕野蛮人
来了
Here I come!
Here I come.
是Faulkner夫人吗
Mrs Faulkner?
是的 我是Bella Faulkner
Yes. Bella Faulkner.
Bella 我是儿童福利院的Paula Hall
Bella, Paula Hall from
这是Ricky Baker
Child Welfare Services. This is Ricky Baker.
Ricky Baker 太好了
Ricky Baker. Yes.
你终于来了
Oh, here you are.
Ricky 我是Bella 你可以叫我Bella
Ricky, I'm Bella. Uh, you can call me Bella,
或者你愿意的话叫阿姨也行
or Auntie, if you like,
虽然我不是你亲阿姨
even though I'm not your real auntie.
但是这样更亲近一点儿嘛
But, you know, it's a bit less formal.
哇喔 你可真是个大胖小子
Whoo. You're a big fella!
你是不是把世界上所有的派都吞肚子里了啊 哈哈
Who ate the guy who ate all the pies, eh?
额 不好意思
Sorry.
他挺不错的
Well, he's nice.
是啊 我们现在有点事情
Yeah. Now, uh, obviously we've
需要好好谈谈 Bella
got a couple of things to talk through, Bella.
之前你肯定已经了解过这孩子的
Clearly you've been briefed about his,
背景情况和收养史了
uh, background and also his foster care history.
很显然 他是个真正的小坏蛋 烫手山芋一个
Apparently he's a bit of a handful, a real bad egg.
我是说 如果你看过他的档案 你就会发现
I mean, if you look at his file, you'll see that for yourself.
这小家伙可真是劣迹斑斑 叛逆 偷窃 乱吐痰 逃家
We're talking disobedience, stealing, spitting, running away,
扔石头 踹东西 毁坏公物
throwing rocks, kicking stuff, defacing stuff,
放火 涂鸦 成天鬼混
burning stuff, loitering and graffiti.
这还只是我们所知道的而已
And that's just the stuff we know about.
但我们希望 通过环境的改变能让他改邪归正
But hopefully, uh, change in scene will help straighten him out.
现在他有家了 他会好起来的
He's home now. He'll be OK.
我喜欢你的乐观 非常好
OK. Well, I like your enthusiasm. Good.
Ricky 这儿就是你的新家了
Ricky, this is your new home.
这小子可难缠了
A real piece of work, this one.
Ricky
Ricky!
已经没有别的人家愿意收留你了 知道吗
There's no one else who wants you, OK?
好了 Ricky 你知道留给你的另一个选择是什么 是吧
Now, Ricky, you know what the alternative is, don't you? Eh?
- 所以这次你能乖乖合作吗 - 当然可以 我们一定可以搞定的
- Think you can make it work? - Course we can. We'll make it work.
让开点 快点 让开点
Move. Move it. Move!
我已经干这行很久了
Yeah. I've been in this game a long time.
我们的口号是“不放弃任何一个孩子 ”
"No child left behind" Is our motto.
好吧 虽然不是官方口号
Well, it's not, you know, the official motto,
但这绝对是我的想法
but it's definitely mine.
另外 我们还要走个交接程序
Also, as part of the transition process,
我需要检查一下你的财产状况
I'll be needing to inspect your property,
确保你这里的收养环境能符合我们的高标准要求
just to make sure that it's up to our high standard.
看起来还不错 你觉得呢 Tappert警官
Looks fine. What do you think, Constable Tappert?
- Andy - 是啊 挺不错的
Andy! Yeah, it looks cool.
好了 我们大约每两个月会来检查一次
Yeah. We'll be coming in every
看看孩子的情况
eight weeks or so, just to check in on, uh...
[“鳄鱼邓迪”为20世纪80年代年澳大利亚拍摄的一个系列电影 男主是一名鳄鱼猎手 由保罗·霍根饰演]
那个“鳄鱼邓迪”是谁啊
Who's that Crocodile Dundee guy over there?
那我的丈夫Hector
Oh, that's my husband, Hector.
哇 他猪猪背了头猪回来
Whoa. He's giving that pig a piggyback.
我看到他有一支来复枪
Well, I see he has a rifle.
小心别让这孩子碰那玩意儿
Just keep it away from this little guy.
天知道他拿了枪会干出什么事儿来
God knows what he's capable of.
好了 他归你了 不得退换哦
OK, he's all yours. No returns.
哈 只是开个玩笑
Oh, I'm just joking.
你有我的电话号码
OK. You've got my number, so just,
如果有问题就打电话给我 好吗
uh, ring me if you've got any trouble. OK?
再见 Ricky
Bye, Ricky.
好吧 反正是见怪不怪了
Wow, what a shocker, eh
走吧 Andy
OK, let's go, Andy.
Ricky 那是Hec 你愿意的话也可以叫他叔叔
Ricky, this is Hec. You can call him Uncle, if you like.
不行 没门儿
No, he can't.
你想做点什么呢 饿了吗
What do you want to do? Are you hungry?
瞧我问这问题是不是傻了 看你这身型就知道了嘛 哈哈哈
That's a silly question, isn't it? Look at you.
你以前在农场干过活吗 还是你根本就是个绣花枕头大草包
You ever worked on a farm before or you just... ornamental?
Hec 想当初我们刚刚相遇的时候
Hec. Just remember when we first met,
你看起来也不怎么样啊
you weren't much good to anyone.
也只不过是个脏兮兮一身酒臭味的流浪汉罢了
Just a scruffy white drifter who smelled like methylated spirits.
晚安
Goodnight.
啊 宝贝你说什么
Eh? What's that, dear?
晚安
Goodnight.
唉...
Oh...
天啊 Hec 你个白痴
Jeez, Hec. You bloody idiot.
怎么了
What?
Ricky
Ricky?
小伙子 你还好吗
Buddy? Are you OK?
别在意Hec说的那些 他就是个老混球罢了
Sorry about Hec. He's a silly old goat, that's all.
好啦 我希望你喜欢你的房间 宝贝
OK, well, I hope you like your room, petal.
他们说你喜欢读书 所以我给你找了些书来
They said you liked to read, so I got a bunch of books for you,
房间里还有个印度台灯
and you'll also notice an Indian lamp,
一个牛头狗台灯 几个猫摆设
a bulldog lamp, and some cats,
还有一把漂亮锋利的小刀 你可以用来杀个夜魔啥的
and a nice sharp knife to kill monsters in the night.
孩子 我知道你曾经历过很多磨难
I can't imagine what you've been through,
你这一路走来肯定不容易
boy. You know, I can't imagine it was easy.
但是现在这儿就是你的家
But you're here now. This is home.
不管怎样 你能来这儿真好
Anyway, it's really nice to have you here,
我在你床上放了个热水袋
and I left a hottie in your bed.
我们明早见
We'll see you in the morning.
好吗
Ok?
好吗 Ricky
OK, Ricky?
好了
Ok.
晚安 早上见
Nigh-night, then. See you in the morning.
上帝啊 孩子 我们找到你真是个奇迹
Jeez, boy, it's a miracle we found you
你居然成功地逃了两百米远
You made it all of 200m.
我只是出来透透气罢了
I was just taking a break.
Hec在做早饭
Hec's cooking breakfast.
有鸡蛋 培根 香肠 还有烤煎饼
Eggs, bacon, a few sossies on the side,... pancakes.
来吧 先把早饭吃了 然后你再逃也不迟
Come on. Have some breakfast, then you can run away.
见鬼 我踩到屎了
Oh man. I got poop on my kicks.
快滚开 臭虫
Go away, insect!
煎饼味道不错
Good pancake.
你的狗叫什么名字
So, what's your dog's name?
Zag
Zag.
[Zag and Zig:澳大利亚电视节目中的两个小丑]
你应该再养一只 叫它Zig
You should get another one and name it Zig.
Bella让我告诉你
Bella told me to tell you that...
你该给我找点活干
you should give me something to do.
你想让我干点什么吗
Is there anything you want me to do?
有啊 离我远点儿
Yeah,... leave me alone.
没问题
Cool.
早上好
Morning.
早上好 我还以为你逃跑了
Morning. I thought you were running away.
我是跑了 但是有东西忘了带 就又回来了
I did, but I forgot something, so I came back.
不错啊 Ricky 看到你这么有积极性真让人高兴
Oh. Good for you, Ricky. Good to see some initiative.
你熟悉这个雨林吗
You ever been up in that jungle before?
哦 这不是雨林 只是个灌木丛而已
Oh, it's not a jungle; it's the bush.
大约有一百万公顷呢 小子
There's about a million hectares of it, buddy.
只是“灌木林”而已吗
You said "Bush".
我就是从那儿来的 那边的深山里面
I'm from up there, deep in the mountains.
你经常回去吗
You ever go back much?
很久没有了 回去一趟不容易啊 很容易迷路
Not for a long time. It's a hard journey, easy to get lost.
那上面有一个湖 名字叫Makutekahu
We got a lake up there called Makutekahu.
湖面宽阔高远 可以一直延伸至天际洇湿天边漂浮的云彩
It's so high up it wets the cloak of the sky.
那里是我们的灵魂升上天堂时的必经之地
It's the first place our spirits go on their way to Reinga.
我的生命终结之时 我也会去那里
Yeah, when my time comes, that's where I'll go too.
你们这里真的有好多死了的东西呢
Man, you guys got a lot of dead stuff round here.
我那天还看见一只死羊 都长蛆了
Saw a dead sheep the other day. Had maggots in it.
无数的蛆
There's heaps of maggots,
在羊身上爬来爬去
maggots wriggling in that sheep
像蠕动的白米一样 真恶心
like moving rice. Yuck.
这是我为蛆编的俳句
That was my haiku about maggots.
名字就叫 “蛆”
It's called "Maggots".
这是负责我心理辅导的女士教我的
This counsellor lady made me do them when I got in trouble.
我有麻烦的时候就编这个 有助于表达我的感受
They help me express my feelings.
- 就是一种诗…… - 我知道什么是俳句
- They're poems made up of... - Yeah. I know what a haiku is.
我写了好多……你还想听听吗
I got heaps of them... want to hear another one?
想啊
Sure.
没问题
Ok.
[Kingi 是本片导演Taika Waititi在2010年执导的另一部影片“ Boy” 中的角色名]
“Kingi 你个杂种”
"Kingi, you wanker.”
“你个狗屎混蛋 我TM的恨死你了”
"You arsehole. I hate you heaps.
“真希望你快点痛苦地死翘翘”
"Please die soon in pain."
这首叫“Kingi 你个杂种”
That was called "Kingi, you Wanker".
够了够了 我知道了 今天不说俳句了
Yeah, yeah. OK. Got ya. Got ya. That's enough haikus for today.
来来 坐下 给我搭把手
Come on. Sit down. Come and give me a hand.
就像这样
Well, it's like this,
再把毛放到袋子里
and then you put it in this bag.
简单吧
Easy.
来吧 这个归你
Here you go. You have a go.
你是不是想干点其他的活啊
Do you want to try something else?
是的 还是干点儿别的吧
Yes, please.
我想象自己是个毛利战士
I'm imagining I'm a Maori warrior,
而那边那个瓶子就是个英国兵
and that bottle over there is a British soldier,
我正在保护我所有的老婆们
and I'm defending all my wives.
[Te Kooti （1832-1893）著名的毛利人游击队领袖和活动家]
好吧 Te Kooti
All right, Te Kooti.
把你的目标
Well, you just keep the
对准你准星上面的这个小凹口
target above the little notch in the sight.
当你准备好以后 就深呼吸 然后...
And then when you're ready, you just breathe-
我勒个去
Bloody hell!
我们要猎什么
So, what are we hunting?
什么都行 运气好的话 说不定能打着鹿
Oh, anything. Deer, if we're lucky.
那边的坡上有群马 我们能开枪打一匹吗
Can we shoot one of those horses up there?
你猜呢 你觉得我会不会同意
Oh, I'll give- I'll give you one guess what my answer will be.
好吧 那么我骑一下总可以吧
Well, can I ride one?
没人可以骑它们 它们太野了
Nobody can ride them; they're too wild.
再说我们为什么要去骑它们啊
Why do they need to be ridden, anyway?
因为它们在那里就是让我们骑的嘛
Well, that's what they're there for.
那就让它们在那里吃吃草
Why can't they just eat
安安分分地当马不行吗
grass and be horses and leave it at that, eh?
好吧 好吧 我只不过是想聊个天嘛
OK, OK. I was just making conversation.
嘘
Shh.
有野猪 快点
Pig! Come on!
什么
What?
哦耶 我们的晚餐搞定了
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo! That's dinner sorted!
想不想帮我把它的内脏挖出来啊
Whoa! Want to help me gut it?
嘿嘿
Hip hip!
万岁
Hooray!
来吹蜡烛吧
Go on, blow out your candles.
好
Ok.
Hector 不如现在给Ricky生日礼物吧
Hector, do you think it's time we gave Ricky his present?
谢谢阿姨 谢谢叔叔
Thank you, Auntie! Thank you, Uncle!
好好喂它 帮它洗澡 它是你的狗了 你要对它负责哦
Feed him, clean up after him. He's yours- you're responsible.
这是我庆祝过的最好的生日了
This is the best birthday I've ever had.
也是我唯一庆祝过的生日
I think it's the only birthday I've ever had.
你要帮它取什么名字
What are you gonna call him?
我还在琢磨 我想取个凶悍点的名字 能表现出它的真实本性的那种
Um, still thinking. Something fierce to reflect its true nature.
[Psycho是精神病患者的意思 Megatron是变形金刚的威震天 Tupac是美国说唱歌手]
比如Psycho啦 Megatron啦 或者叫Tupac
Either Psycho, Megatron... or Tupac.
Tupac 是什么
What's a Tupac?
他是我... 他是一个很酷的说唱歌手 他就像是我最好的朋友
It's just my- this really cool rapper,and he's, like, my best friend.
你今晚打算逃跑吗
Are you gonna run away tonight?
还不确定
Not sure.
没事的 我无所谓的啦
No, oh, it's cool with me.
只要你保证在吃早餐前能回来就行了
Just make sure you're back by breakfast.
好的
Ok.
能和你在一起我们真的很高兴 小家伙
So happy we found you, buddy.
很抱歉没能早点找到你
Sorry it took so long.
我也是
Me too.
晚安 Ricky
Nigh-night, Ricky.
晚安 阿姨
Night, Auntie.
你要去哪里 Tupac
Where are you going, Tupac?
过来
Come on.
兄弟
Man!
噢
Ohhh!
天啊 Bella
Oh, Bella!
老天啊
God!
有时候 在生命里
You know, sometimes in life,
看起来似乎已经无路可走
it seems like there's no way out-
你就好像是一只绵羊 被困在了由狼群设计的迷宫中
like a sheep trapped in a maze designed by wolves.
但事实是 当你陷入这种困境的时候
And you know that if you're ever in that situation,
面前总会有两扇门可以让你选择
there are always two doors to choose from.
当你通过第一扇门的时候...
And through the first door- oh,
当然第一扇门嘛 是很容易通过的
it's easy to get through that door-
在门的另一边等着你的
and on the other side waiting for
是你可以想象到的各种美味的东西
you are all the nummiest treats you can imagine-
芬达 玉米片 派罗瓦柠檬汽水 汉堡圈 无糖可乐
Fanta, Doritos, L&P, Burger Rings, Coke Zero.
但你知道吗 还有另外一扇门
But you know what? There's also another door,
不是汉堡圈的门 也不是芬达的门
not the Burger Ring door, not the Fanta door;
是另外一扇更难通过的门
another door that's harder to get through.
猜猜门里边有什么东西 有人想要来猜一猜吗
Guess what's on the other side? Anyone want to take a guess?
蔬菜吗
Vegetables?
不 不是蔬菜
N-No, not vegeta-
不是
No.
是耶稣吗
WOMAN : Jesus?
我就知道你可能会想到耶稣
You would think Jesus. I thought
我开始也以为是耶稣来着 在我...在我第一次通过那扇门的时候
Jesus the first time I-I-I-I came across that door.
不是耶稣啦 里面是另外一扇门
It's not Jesus. It's another door.
那猜猜这扇门里面会是什么
And guess what's on the other side of that door?
耶稣
Jesus.
耶稣 对 是耶稣
Jesus. Yeah, Jesus.
耶稣可真够狡猾的 是吧
He's tricky like that, Jesus.
所以我们一起来向耶稣祷告吧
So let us pray, to Jesus, please,
祈祷他能让我们更容易地
and make it a bit easier
通过那些门 去发现自我
to get through those doors, uh, to find you
以及那些不计其数的美味点心
and your bounty of delicious confectionary.
谢谢你 Selena 开始吧
Thank you, Selena. Take it away.
BGM-"The old rugged cross"
这是晚餐 有点烤焦了
Dinner. It's a bit burnt.
给你
Here.
把这封信
Read this.
大声读出来
Out loud.
来自儿童福利院
"From the Child Welfare people.
Hector Faulkner 先生
"Mr Hector Faulkner.
我是儿童福利院的Paula Hall
"This is Paula Hall from Child Welfare writing to you.
我很遗憾得知你最近丧偶的消息
"I'm sorry to hear about your recent bereavement.
然而 鉴于环境的改变
"However, in light of the altered circumstances,
我们需要根据目前的状况
"The current situation
重新考虑并审核你们收养Ricky的计划
regarding Ricky's care will have to be reviewed.
6月1日之后 我们将会把他带回福利院进行看护
"As of June the 1st, I will be taking him back into state custody
直到我们作出能够替代的安排
"Until alternative arrangements can be made.
请放心 我一定会尽心尽力地给Ricky找到一个新的家庭
"Rest assured I am working tireless to find a new home for Ricky.
因此下周我们将上门来接走Ricky
"And you can expect a visit next week for Ricky's collection.
谨致以诚挚的问候 来自儿童福利部的Paula Hall
"Sincerely, Paula Hall, Ministry of Child Welfare."
该死 他们不可以这么做
Like hell! They can't do that!
是的 他们可以
Yeah, they can.
可我现在在这里生活 这里就是我的家
But I live here now. It's my home!
已经不再是了 至少在他们看来 不是
Not any more, it isn't. Not in their eyes.
没有一个女人持家 就不算家
Not without a woman to run the show.
要不你重新娶个老婆怎么样
Why don't we just get you a new wife?
我听说网络上有很多女人
There's plenty of ladies on the internet, I heard.
太快了吗
Too soon?
那我们就坚持继续在这里生活
What if we just keep living here,
如果他们想把农场抢走
and if they try to take the farm,
我们就跟他们枪战 誓死捍卫到底 就像电影那样
we'll just have a shootout, like Scarface.
虽然我们没有可卡因
Except we don't have any cocaine.
Ricky 没用的
You can't change this, Ricky.
你必须要回去了
You're gonna go back,
他们会给你找个新家的 好吗
and you're gonna stick it out in a new home. OK?
这是不可能的 没门儿
There's no way that's happening.
我会进灌木林里住些日子 我需要...  消失一段时间
Well, I'm gonna go bush. I'm gonna... disappear for a while.
消失 这听起来更像是我要做的事
Disappear? Yeah, that sounds more like me.
别这样嘛 我们可是一伙的
Come on! We'll be a team!
老天啊 你在那里面连五分钟都呆不了
Oh, for God's sake. You wouldn't last five minutes out there.
Bella阿姨说过 你得好好照顾我
But Auntie Bella said you had to look after me
你可以给我点私人空间吗
Can you just give me some privacy?
我听说他们会在福利院做实验
I heard they do experiments at the Boys' Home-
水刑啊 折磨啊之类的事
waterboarding, torture, that sort of thing.
有个男孩只是想多要点早餐麦片
This one boy got thrown acid
脸上就被泼硫酸了
on his face because he asked for more Weet-Bix.
嘿 你不能把阿姨就这么放到个箱子里
Hey, you can't put Auntie in a box.
够了 别说了
Give it a rest.
- 但是她是想要去天堂的啊  - 她已经不在了 好吗
- But she wanted to go to the sky place. - She's gone, OK?
这就是人生 前一天你还在这里
That's life- one day you're here,
下一天你就被装在个该死的盒子里了
and the next you're in a bloody box.
孩子 你给我听好
Just get this into your head,boy
是Bella想要你和我们一起生活 不是我
it was Bella that wanted you here, not me.
你觉得你可以留在这里 但事实上不行
I know you think this can work, but it can't.
福利院的人这个星期五就会过来
So the welfare people are coming on Friday.
他们会把你带走
They're coming to get you.
所以 就只能这样了吗
That's that, then?
对 只能这样了
Yep... that's that.
只能这样了
That's that.
我在这个谷仓里自焚了
永别了这个残酷的世界
不信你自己进去看
再见 Ricky Baker
Goodbye, Ricky Baker.
天啊
Uh-oh.
快走 Tupac 快走 Tupac
Come on, Tupac! Come on, Tupac!
BGM-"Ocean blue"
啊
Whoa!
吃了五片 还剩十片 加油 Ricky 坚持定量 省着点吃
Five down, 10 to go. Come on, Ricky. Stick on the rations.
我受够了 Tupac 我们回家吧
Stuff this, Tupac. We're going home.
你迷路了吗
Are you lost?
没有
No.
是的 你迷路了
Yeah, you are.
我告诉过你 你在这里待不过五分钟的
Told you you wouldn't last more than five minutes out here.
你已经完全绕晕了头 老实说你个路痴的程度连我都感到惊讶
You got yourself very lost. I'm amazed how lost you got.
我可是走得很快的 而且我已经在这里建立了我自己的世界
I move fast. I've got my own thing going on here-
Ricky小镇 人口  Ricky一个
Ricky Town. Population- Ricky.
是吗 现在是你回到现实小镇的时候了
Yeah, well. You're going back to Reality Town.
没门儿 我就住在这里了
Like hell. I live here now.
才怪
Like hell.
给我听好 跟在灌木林里转来转去浪费时间找你这个小混蛋相比
I've got better things to do than to run around the bush
老子要做的重要事情可多了去了
looking for little shits like you.
- 所以赶紧的 给我起来 - 我讨厌你
- So get up. - I hate you.
正好 我也讨厌你
Well, I hate you too.
你去死吧
I hope you die.
你也去死吧
Me too!
你不如现在就把我杀了吧
You may as well just kill me now.
不要杀我
Don't kill me.
反正能回城市的话 我也挺高兴的
Anyway, I'm excited to go back to the city.
很好
Good.
我等不及了 我讨厌这里 到处都是泥巴
Can't wait. I hate it here- so much dirt.
城市生活就很酷
It's going to be cool.
可以搞点新货色 当个毒贩子
Get me some new gears, become a drug dealer,
做个饶舌歌手  然后遇到飞车扫射 横尸街头什么的
a rapper, and die in a drive-by.
专心看好你前面的路
Just keep an eye on where you're going.
我都湿透了
This is wet.
我肚子饿了 我们在哪里啊
I'm hungry. Where are we?
闭嘴
Shut it.
我讨厌灌木丛
I hate the bush.
闭嘴
Shut it.
我鞋都湿啦
My shoes are wet.
还不是因为你这没用的小混蛋迷路了
You're the useless bugger who got lost in the first place.
给我记住
You remember that.
你连地图都没有么 地图呢
You don't even have a map. Where's our map?
不需要 我知道自己的位置
Don't need one. I know where I am.
就算有你也看不懂吧
Probably couldn't even read it anyway.
我为啥非要看懂地图啊
Why would I need to read a map?
跟你说了 我知道自己的位置  再说了 阅读是愚蠢的
I already told you- I know where I am. Reading is stupid anyway.
只有文盲才会这样说
Only people who can't read say things like that.
怎么啦
What?
不会吧 你不识字吗
No. You can't read?!
说话小心点 伙计
Watch it, pal.
你就像那种
You're like one of those people who are,
被狼之类的野兽养大的家伙 对吧
like, raised by, like, wolves or something, eh?
哈喽啊 偶 Hec 偶 字 不识
Ooga booga! Me Hec- me no read!
这是啥 是字哎 偶 蠢
What's this? This is words. Me stupid.
你个小杂...
You little bast...
我的脚
Ah, my foot.
没事吧
You OK?
不 我有事 都怪你 你个小杂种
No. I'm not OK. This is all your fault, you little bastard!
来吧 我扶你一把
Come on, let's get you comfortable.
我不是真的认为你是杂种
I don't really think you're a bastard.
不 你确实是这么认为的 但没关系啊 你也是杂种
Yeah, you do. That's OK, because I think you're a bastard too.
不管怎么样 这样才好 说出来就好了
Anyway, it's good. It's... healthy to get these feelings out.
还动不了吗
Can you move it yet?
废话 我的腿骨折了 很久才会好
'Course I can't. It's fractured. Take weeks to heal.
[Debbie Downer 《周六夜现场》中的角色 总是用消极眼光做评判]
好吧 Debbie Downer 咱能想点积极的事儿吗
OK, Debbie Downer, can we think of something more positive?
或许 你可以试试写个俳句 抒发下情感
Maybe you could... write a haiku to express your feelings.
写个什么
A what?
迷失于丛林
Lost in the forest.
疼痛的脚踝 可怜的叔叔
A sore ankle, poor uncle.
也罢 已释怀
Oh well, never mind.
哎呦老天 我们得赶快离开这地方
Oh God, we really need to get out of here.
你要我去找人帮忙吗
Do you want me to go find help?
但是我活不到那时候 对吧
I'd die, wouldn't I?
算了 我们别无选择 只能在这儿露营一段时间了
No, we've got no choice but to camp out here for a few weeks.
但是我饿了
But I'm hungry!
丛林里有足够的食物 只要你会找
There's plenty to eat if you know where to look.
但是我不知道去哪里找 Hector
Well, I don't know where to look,Hector.
还有 我厕纸也用完了
And also, I ran out of toilet paper.
把你的给我用下
Give me some of yours.
啥
Eh?
我要拉便便 我需要拉屎 你需要拉屎 大家都需要拉屎
I've gotta poop. I need a poop, you need a poop. We all poop.
用树叶
Use a leaf.
树叶
A leaf?
我恨你
I hate you.
然后把屎埋了
And bury it!
把你埋了还差不多
I'll bury you.
这才不是那娃儿烧焦的尸体
This ain't no charred foster kid.
你咋知道 Paula
How can you tell, Paula?
你觉得这像人头吗 Andy
Does this look like a human head to you, Andy?
你在哪里 Ricky Baker
Where are you, Ricky Baker?
那个 我猜是那个老头把他宰了 然后埋掉
Hey, I reckon the old man chopped him up, buried him somewhere-
或者吃掉了
Or ate him.
绝对是出事儿了 但到底是什么事呢
Something definitely happened, but I'm wondering what.
够了 Andy 把你的嘴闭上
OK, I'm gonna need you to shut up,Andy,
你快烦死我了
because you're doing my frickin' head in.
好了 我们走
Come on, let's go.
这事儿肯定还没完
This ain't over by a Mangaweka mile.
找警察来 这可是紧急事件
Get me the police. It's an emergency.
喂 等下 Paula 我就是警察啊
Hey, whoa, Paula. I am the police.
我是说真正的警察 Andy 带枪的那种
I mean real ones, Andy. Ones with guns.
嘿 叔叔 想听随身听吗
Hey, Uncle, wanna listen to my Walkman?
不想
No.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
打猎
Hunting.
打你个头啊
Like hell.
你等会儿就知道谢谢我了
You can thank me later.
Tupac
Tupac!
来 来
Yeah, yeah.
打到猎物了吗
Did you get any food?
那是什么玩意儿
What the hell is that?
沙拉
Salad.
怎么了 你行你上啊
What? I'd like to see you do any better.
我还从没吃过呢 你鼻涕虫从哪儿弄来的
Never eaten a slug before. Where did you get it?
这是鳗鱼好么 在小溪下游抓到的
It's an eel. Got it down the creek.
我知道 但怎么抓呀 拿什么抓的
Yeah, but how? With what?
我也不知道 小技巧吧
Oh, I don't know. The knack.
哦 小技巧 什么技巧 你怎么学到的
Oh yeah, the knack. What's that? How do you get it?
也不算什么技巧吧 就是...
It's not a thing. It's just-
就这样抓到了 这是..
You just get it. It's a...
这是一种方法
Oh, it's a way of, um-
一种不需要想太多 也不需要说太多
it's a way of figuring things out without having to think too hard or...
就能捉摸出来的一种方法
or talk, more importantly.
你知道 大多数死于丛林里的人 被发现的时候都是赤身裸体的
You know, most people who die in the bush- they're found naked.
妈呀
Ew.
嗯 他们太害怕了
Yeah, they panic, and they
觉得身上的衣服一种拖累
think their clothes are slowing them down.
就把衣服扔了 然后就被冻死了
They throw them away, and then the cold gets to them.
但生存的窍门是 一种技巧
But the trick is- this is the knack-
你要保持冷静 寻找水源 顺着它向高处走
you stay calm, you look for water, you follow it to high ground
直到能够看清方位
until you can see what's going on.
如果之前我走失了 你会怎么办 会想念我吗
What would you do if I got lost today? Would you miss me?
你没有走失 所以 这很好
Well, you- you didn't get lost, so... that's good.
你想念Bella阿姨吗
Do you miss Auntie Bella?
嗯 你还没走出来
Yeah, you're still processing.
难过的事情发生后你要这么做 你要走出来
You got to do that when sad things happen- process it.
就像我的朋友Amber死了之后 我花了很长时间才走出来
That's like when my mate Amber died. I processed that for ages.
谁是Amber
Who's Amber?
我们都被同个家庭收养过一段时间
We were in a home together for a while,
然后她去了一个新家
and she went to this new
然后就惹上了很多麻烦
family and then started getting in trouble,
她说了新爸爸的事儿
telling stories about the dad.
然后有一天 她就死了
And then one day she was just dead.
死了 怎么死的
What do you mean dead? How?
不知道 没人告诉我
Don't know. No one told me.
这个鼻涕虫真的蛮好吃的
This slug is actually pretty good.
好了 是时候离开这儿了
Come on, it's time to get out of here.
太好了 太好了 太太太 太好了
Yes! Yes! Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes! Yes!
好了 晚上我们就住这了
OK. We'll stay here the night,
明天下午 我们就会回到农场了
and we'll be back at the farm by tomorrow arvo.
棒呆啦
Yes!
有床 还有书
There's beds, books!
棒呆啦 棒呆啦 棒呆啦 超棒 还有厕纸
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes! Toilet paper!
- 还有暖暖的火炉 - 外面待着 小子们
- A nice, warm fire. - Get out, you mongrels.
拜托 拜托 给我点信号
Come on. Come on. Give me some bars
这样我才能跟外世取得联系啊
so I can communicate with the outside world.
Ricky
Ricky,...
过来看看这个
take a look at this.
哦 叔叔 我们出名了
Oh, Uncle. We're famous!
警 方 开 始 搜 捕
叔叔 我们出名了
Oh, Uncle. We're famous!
开 始 搜 捕
叔叔 我们出名了
Oh, Uncle. We're famous!
搜 捕
叔叔 我们出名了
Oh, Uncle. We're famous!
搜 捕
"Hector Faulkner 65岁 Richard Baker 13岁"
"Hector Faulkner, 65, and Richard Baker, 13,
"已经失踪6周"
"Have been missing now for six weeks."
"Faulkner是高...
"Faulkner is Cauc..."
[Caucasian 高加索人 即白人]
"高...亚洲人"
"Cauc... Asian."
哇 他们真该去看看眼科了 你明显是白人嘛
Wow, they got that wrong, because you're obviously white.
"人们担心在Faulkner的妻子死后"
"There is a fear for Faulkner's
"他的精神状态变得不稳定"
mental health following the recent death of his wife.
"警方不排除绑架的可能性" 绑架哎
"Police are not ruling out kidnapping." Kidnapping!
"护林人已经发出警告"
"Park rangers have been alerted for anyone seeing the pair"
"若看到这俩人 务必向附近的警局报告"
"Should report back to the nearest police station." Ho!
叔叔 现在你基本上已经是个犯人了哎
Uncle, you're basically a criminal now.
不过 好处是 你出名了
But on the bright side, you're famous.
他们认为我疯了
They think I'm crazy.
还以为你是亚洲人
And Asian.
喂 听听 角马迁徙的时候
Hey, you know when the Wildebeests migrate,
要跋涉上千英里
they walk up to a thousand miles.
很远吗
Is that heaps?
嗯 很远
Yeah. Heaps.
跟我们一样
Just like us.
走啊 走啊 努力抵达某处
Walking, walking, trying to get somewhere.
寻找一个更温暖的家
Looking for a better home.
你们好啊
Gidday.
你们好
老天 你们得好好解释一下
Jeez, eh. Whoo. Got a lot of explaining to do.
大家可都在找你们
A lot of people looking for you two.
嗯 我们知道
Yeah, we know.
之前在山林里我弄伤了脚踝
I did my ankle back in one of the valleys.
我们 准备回去了
And, uh, we're on the way out now.
好吧
Well,...
等他们知道我们在小屋里找到你们 才能回去
wait till they hear we caught you in a hut.
我们可没躲 这孩子自己迷路了
Well, we weren't hiding. The boy got himself lost,
而我是来把他带回去的
and, uh, I'm bringing him back.
哟呵 枪不错啊 伙计 这枪拿来干嘛 打麻雀吗
Whoa. Cool gun, bro. What do you guys shoot with this? Sparrows?
嗯...有时候吧
Mm, sometimes.
他伤害你了吗 孩子
He hurt you, son?
没 只是有一次摔进了带刺的灌木丛里
Nah. I fell in some prickles one time.
是他把你推进去的吗
Did he push you in those prickles?
有可能啊 是他推你进去的吗 小兄弟
Yeah, probably. Did he push you in the prickles, mate?
别调戏他了
Leave him alone.
你给我闭嘴 老东西
You shut your trap, old fulla.
我要是你的话我就去一边儿休息一下
I'd go get some rest if I was you.
明天你还有很长的路要走呢
You've got a long walk tomorrow.
首先 跟我说话的时候你给我悠着点
First of all, you watch how you talk to me.
其次
And second of all,
你能带走他 但是我要留下
you can take him, but I'm staying here.
没门 人们想知道答案
Like hell. People want answers.
对 答案
Yeah, answers.
听着 我们迷路了 我受了伤
Look, we got lost; I got injured.
他完好无损 基本算是放了个假
He's fine. It was basically a holiday.
也不真放假 因为他让我干事情
Not a real holiday, because he made me do stuff.
什么事情
Like what?
就 那事儿呗 他腿脚不便 所以就让我帮他做
Just stuff. He had a sore leg, so he made me do things for him.
一开始挺难的
It was hard at first,
因为我的手太柔软细嫩了 但慢慢我就习惯了
because my hands are so soft. But I got used to it.
我也不愿意的
I didn't really want to do it,
可是不这么做我又小命不保
but it was the only way to survive.
也不是一直都很难 有时候我也会帮自己做一下
Well, it wasn't always hard. Sometimes I got to do my own thing.
尽管他几乎从不和我一起做
He pretty much never joined in with me, though.
我问他想不想和我一起做 但
I asked if he wanted to play with me, but...
他都会让我自己一边快活去
he would just make me play with myself.
恶心 太恶心了 恶心死了
I feel sick. I feel sick, Hugh.
等等 他不是那个意思
Well- Hang on. He doesn't know what he means.
你个该死的变态
You're a bloody pervert.
你叫我什么
What did you call me?
你听到他说的了
You heard him.
没错 你听到了 你个老变态
Yeah, you heard him, you old perv.
喂 他不是变态 你个傻逼
Hey! He's not a pervert, you dickhead!
闭嘴 Ricky
Shut up, Ricky.
对 闭嘴 Ricky
Yeah, shut up, Ricky.
喂 只有我能叫他闭嘴
Hey, only I get to tell him to shut up.
死开 你这给人洗脑的货
Oooh. Brainwasher.
你要去蹲监狱了 你个变态
You're going to jail, you pervert.
你刚说什么
Want to say that again?
再说一遍试试
Say it again.
去蹲监狱
Going to jail,...
你个变态
you pervert.
滚开 你个杂种
Get off, you mongrel!
要动真格了
Shit just got real!
都给我退后 放开我叔叔
Back up, homies, and let go of my uncle!
没事的 孩子 你可以把枪放下 他不会再伤害你了
It's OK, kid. You can put it down. He won't hurt you anymore.
我说放开我叔叔
I said get away from my uncle.
Ricky 把枪给我
Ricky, give me that.
趴下
Get down!
Ricky 把他们的枪拿走 枪栓都卸掉
Ricky, get their guns. Take the bolts out.
我们要上路了
We're getting out of here.
没错 要动真格了
Yeah. Shit just got real.
等下
Hey!
你死定了 老头子
You're dead, old man.
对 你完蛋了 老变态
Yeah, dead meat, you old perv!
你已经被盯上了 老兄 你跑不掉的
You've had it, mate! There's no chance for you!
起来
Get up.
老实说刚才那是我干过的最黑帮的事了
Straight up that was the most gangster shit I've ever done.
你个蠢货 还有 刚才在那你都说了些什么鬼东西啊
You idiot. And what were you talking about back there?
你知道你的话给人什么感觉吗
Do you know what that sounds like?
不知道
No!
哎哟卧槽
Ohhh!
他们肯定会让我蹲号子的
They're gonna put me away for sure.
一群混蛋
Bastards.
是啊 一群混蛋 听到那家伙怎么叫我了吧 变态
Yeah, bastards. Hear what that guy called me? Pervert!
我们需要更多的枪
We need more guns,...
我的天 我该怎么办
Oh God. What am I gonna do?
手榴弹
... hand grenades,...
想一想 动动脑子
Think. I've got to think.
- 也许再来个火箭筒 - 他们会来抓我们的
- ... maybe a rocket launcher. - They're gonna come for us.
没错 警察
Yeah, Police.
真棒啊
Awesome.
不 这一点都不棒 Ricky 这不是在闹着玩
No, it's not awesome, Ricky, it's serious.
我知道 但没人受伤 所以你不是危险分子
Yeah, but no one got hurt. You're not dangerous.
是啊 但他们觉得是
Yeah, well, I am to them.
我蹲过号子
I've been to prison.
很好这很黑帮 犯了什么事
Gangster! For what?
过失杀人
Manslaughter.
超级黑帮啊
Double gangster!
[出狱后代表在拘留期间有所爱之人死亡]
你需要个泪珠纹身
You need a teardrop tattoo.
那时候我还年轻 酒后闹事
Oh, I was young. It was a drunken fight.
我付出了代价 但 他们还是会狗眼看人低
Did my time, but... they won't see it like that.
我可以告诉他们你只是出来找我而已
I'll just tell them you were looking after me.
你和他们说什么都没用
It doesn't matter what you tell them;
他们不会信你的 他们会觉得是我逼你那么说的
they won't believe you. They'll think I made you do it.
我不想再蹲监狱了 我宁愿住在山上
I'm not going back to jail. I'm better off up here.
这地方不适合小孩子
This is no place for a kid.
你必须得回去 Ricky
You're going to have to go back, Ricky.
回哪儿
To what?
回福利中心的人那里去
Well, to the welfare people.
- 不要 - 他们会照顾你的
- No. - They'll look after you.
不 他们才不会
No, they won't.
他们会给你找个新家 没事的
They'll find you another home. You'll be fine.
不 你都不好好听我说 大家都是一个样
No. You're not listening! Nobody listens.
不会有什么新家的 只有少管所
There's no more homes, just juvie!
少管所是什么鬼地方
What's juvie?
少年犯管教所
Juvenile prison.
他们完全不关心像我这样的孩子
They don't care about kids like me.
他们只是不停地踢皮球
They just keep moving us around until...
直到我们自行毁灭 就像Amber一样
something happens, like... Amber.
天啊 那真够讨厌的
Oh, no. Bugger that.
好吧 好吧 我们在数百万公顷的丛林里 还挺大的
OK, OK. We're in about a million hectares of bush- that's big.
够我们在里面躲上一阵子了
It's big enough to enough to hide in for a while, anyway.
我没意见
Good enough for me.
但就快到冬天了
But we're heading into winter.
会很难熬 没有小屋 没有帐篷 真正的丛林生活
It's gonna be rough- no huts, no tents, real bush life.
你能应付吗
Can you handle that?
我能应付得来
I can handle it.
好 如果你给我惹麻烦 我就把你丢下
Yeah. And if you play up, I dump ya.
没问题 叔叔
OK, Uncle.
我还是不喜欢你叫我叔叔
I'd still prefer if you don't call me Uncle.
好吧 Hec 我们下一步怎么做
OK, Hec. So what do we do now?
我们跑路
We run.
等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
不 不
No, no.
不对 我们用不着跑
No, we don't need to run.
是啊 我们改快走就好
Oh yeah. Let's just fast walk.
对 走吧
Yeah. Come on.
好 好 好 好 太好了
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
相当壮观 是吧
Pretty majestical, eh?
我觉得没有那么个单词
I don't think that's a word.
壮观 当然有了
Majestical? Sure it is.
不 那不是真的
Nah, it's not real.
你怎么知道不是
What would you know?
应该是 壮丽
It's "Majestic."
听上去没什么区别啊
Well, that doesn't sound very special.
壮观 听上去更好点
"Majestical" Is way better.
你觉得这地方应该叫什么
What do you reckon this place is called, anyway?
你觉得这里会不会
Do you think it's that place
就是传说中外套会被天空弄湿的地方
where the cloak gets wet by the sky or something?
我不知道 那他妈是什么鬼
I don't know. What the hell does that mean?
Bella阿姨说她是从这儿来的
Auntie Bella said she was from up here-
从这个几乎连接天际的特殊的湖
from this special lake that almost touches the sky.
伙计 Bella不知道她自己从哪儿来的
Mate, Bella didn't know where she was from.
不 她说了
Nah, she said-
不 那都是她编的
No. She was making it up.
听着 Bella没有任何家人 就像你我一样
Look, Bella didn't have any family. Like you. Like me.
所以她才想要照顾你 还有同情我
That's why she wanted to look after you... and took pity on me.
她想解救我们这些被所有人拒之门外的可怜虫
She wanted to save us poor wretches when no one else wanted us.
就像搜救犬一样
Like rescue dogs.
这就是她的为人 有颗金子般的心
That's the way she was. Heart of gold.
没错 这很壮观
Yeah, it's majestical.
赶紧搭帐篷吧 好吗
May as well camp, eh?
太阳快要落山了
Sun is going down.
事件新进展 更多关于这次大规模全国搜捕的消息
Developing story now, more on this massive national manhunt.
没错 我们邀请了来自
Yes, we've got Paula Hall
儿童福利部的Paula Hall
from the Department of Child Welfare with us.
Paula 欢迎你
Paula, thank you for being here...
- 早上好 - 和我们谈谈这个男孩
- Good morning. - Tell us about this boy.
他是个怎样的孩子
What kind of character are we talking about?
听着 我们
Well, look, we're-
我们谈论的这个小男孩是个擅长偷窃
We're talking about a young boy who is capable of stealing,
随地吐痰 乱踢乱砸 破坏公物
spitting, breaking stuff, kicking stuff, defacing stuff,
偷东西 烧东西
stealing stuff, burning stuff and,
胡乱涂鸦的人
uh, loitering and graffiti-ing. Yeah.
即便如此 Paula 他还只是个孩子
Mm. Even so, Paula, he's just a kid,
是吧 他孤身一人在丛林里 他肯定很害怕
right? He's alone in the bush. He's scared.
害什么怕 不 不 他不怕 他不是个胆小的孩子
Scared? No, no. He's not- He's not a scared little kid.
他是个乱动的扳手
He's a spanner in the works,
而我是那个负责抓住扳手
and I'm the mechanic who is gonna take that spanner
- 并把它放回工具箱的修理工 - 好吧
- and put him back in the toolbox. - OK.
把他放到属于他的地方 不放弃任何一个孩子 不放弃任何一个孩子
... where he belongs. No child left behind. No child left behind.
不放弃任何一个孩子
No child left behind.
他会知道这话是什么意思的
He'll know what that means.
好吧
Ok.
找到了吗
Any luck?
我们在绿色区域的某处
We're somewhere in this green bit.
这里曾经有人居住 我们还不算迷路
Well, people used to live here, so we can't be that lost.
说不定他们也迷路了
They probably got lost too,
然后就放弃了 我们大概也会死在这里
and then just gave up. We'll probably die here.
知道了就闭嘴吧
Well, anything to shut you up.
只要那只蠢鸟闭嘴我也会闭嘴的
I'll shut up if that stupid bird shuts up.
闭嘴 死鸟
Shut up, stupid bird!
看着
Just watch.
没见过这么迟钝的鸟
Huh. Never seen a dumb bird like that before.
好好看着
Just watch.
是只垂耳鸦
It's a huia.
[新西兰特有的珍稀鸟类]
我觉得那鸟是垂耳鸦
I reckon that bird was a huia.
这种鸟应该灭绝了才对
Supposed to be extinct.
那很稀罕啊
That's pretty rare.
伙计 肯定有很多人
Mate,... I reckon there'd be a lot
想要看看这种珍稀动物
of people interested in seeing something like that.
发现它们的人肯定会...出名
And the people who discovered them would be... pretty famous.
对 说不定还能赚点钱
Yeah, probably some money in it too.
友情提示 我们还需要照片作证呢
Mind you, need some photos to prove it.
但我们没有照相机
We don't have a camera.
你上次洗澡是什么时候
When was the last time you washed?
大概一个月前
About a month ago.
明显洗得不够勤快啊 是吧
Well, that's not enough, eh?
好了 伙计 我们走吧
OK, mate. Let's go.
你那里有什么发现
What have you got there mate?
嗯 哦 几本书
Huh? Oh books.
几本书 去你的书 找点吃的和暖和的东西
Books? Bloody books. Look for food and warm stuff.
好吧 好吧 好吧 别那么心急
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Keep your pants on.
天哪 是护林员
Jeez. That's a ranger.
他死了
Oh, he's dead.
老天
Oh Jeez.
伙计 你还好吗 你怎么了
You all right, mate? What's the matter?
Ricky 我们得做点什么
Ricky, we've got to do something.
你不会要杀人分尸吧
Are you going to manslaughter him?
我可受不了这么血腥的场面
Because I don't think I can watch.
不是 你个熊孩子 我 我们必须帮他一把
No, you idiot. I'm- We've got to get him some help.
外面有条通向河流的小路
There's a track down to a river;
有几户人家住在林子里
there's some bush people that live down there.
大概要走上两个小时
It's about a two-hour trek.
我们可以在天黑前走到那里
We can make it before dark.
好吧 但总要有人留下来照顾这个人啊
Well, someone has got to stay behind and look after this bloke.
那你慢慢照顾吧
Have fun.
别到处乱逛 跟着路径走
Now don't go wandering; just stick to the tracks.
如果实在没招了
If you get desperate,...
就吃了你的狗
eat your dog.
什么
What?
你不会有事的 伙计
You'll be right, mate.
赶紧回来就行了 知道不
Just bloody well come back, OK?
好吧
Ok.
你在那里干什么呢 傻孩子
What do you think you're doing out here, freaky kid?
卡灵顿那儿的木屋里有人病倒了
There's a sick man up at Carrington Hut.
他没法走路 也没法呼吸
He can't walk, and he's having trouble breathing.
你能不能叫个直升飞机来
Can you radio in a chopper?
好吧 没问题
OK. Sweet as.
对 请尽快派一架直升飞机过来 完毕
"Uh, yeah, we need a helicopter up here ASAP. Over."
我看起来像是带了对讲机吗
Does it look like I carry a radio?
他生什么病了
What's wrong with him?
我不知道 也许快要死了
I don't know. He might be dying.
呃 好吧 过来 我们去打电话叫警察过来
Ew. Oh, OK. Come on, we'll go call the cop.
上来吧 小子
Get on, man.
Bruce 我已经告诉你了 在卡灵顿那个木屋里
I've already told you, Bruce- up at Carrington Hut.
他大概已经死了
He's probably already dead by now.
想要点冰激凌吗
Do you want some ice cream?
我怎么知道 有点责任心 飞过去看一眼
How should I know? Do your job, fly up there and take a look.
我已经告诉你了 你老是不听
I already told you that, but you're not listening.
是的 我可以 嗯...
Oh, yes, I do. I can. Uh...
想吃香肠吗
You want a sausage?
对 对 快去 我会跟他说的 再见
Yeah, yeah. Do that. Yeah, I'll tell him. Laters.
明天一早他们就会过去
They're gonna head up there first thing in the morning.
那我得赶紧走了
Better go, then.
我要先走一步去警告我叔叔
Got to get there before they do so I can warn Uncle...
放松 兄弟 我知道你是谁
Relax, bro. I know who you are.
我在报纸上看到过你的照片
I've seen your picture in the paper.
只是你实际上要瘦一点
Except you're skinnier in real life.
你父母在哪里
Where's your parents?
死了
Dead.
不是 开玩笑 我 爸爸
Nah, jokes. My, um, dad,
他跟我叔叔在看球赛 而我妈妈
he's watching the league with my uncle, and my mum,
她在旅馆那边工作
she's working at the lodge.
你想抽烟吗
Do you want to smoke a joint?
不 我乱说的 我不抽烟 我就是话多而已
Nah, I'm just being a dick. I don't smoke. I'm talking heaps eh?
对 他们说我的话太多了
Yeah, people say I talk too much.
你不怎么说话是吧 我这人一开口就停不下来
You don't talk much, eh? I can talk for ages.
只要你愿意听我说 如果你不愿意的话
If you want me to talk for ages, or if you don't me to talk,
那就直接告诉我你不想听我说话
just tell me if you don't want me to talk.
就好像 有一次我在学校 一直说个不停
Like, this one time I was school, and I was talking too much,
然后老师走进来
and the teacher walks in-
我没听她说话 因为她是我阿姨...
I'm not listening to her, because she's my Auntie...
但我就是说个不停
But then I just kept talking-
[战士队是新西兰联盟橄榄球队的专业队伍]
嗨 小家伙 那些所谓的战士真是毫无用处 妈蛋
Hey, bub. Far out those bloody Warriors are useless! Koretux.
我爸爸
That's my dad.
他们烦死我了
They are killing me.
喂
Hey.
你是那个人 你是你 是那个人
You're him. You're you! That's him!
哦 Ricky Bake光临寒舍 你想不想 吃点什么
Oh, Ricky Baker in my house. You want, uh, anything?
比如香肠 我们有的是香肠 兄弟 远比
Sausage, bro? We've got heaps of sausages, brother. Far...
我不想问你这个 Ricky 但如果不问的话我会后悔
I hate to ask you this, Ricky, but I'll kick myself if I don't.
嗯
Um,...
能跟你一起自拍吗
Can I have a selfie, please?
可以吗 可以吧
Yeah? Yeah?
哇 我的天哪 别人知道了肯定会闹翻天的
Far! Oh my goodness. The boys are gonna be buzzing on this one.
笑起来 笑起来
Big smile. Big smile.
沮丧脸 沮丧脸
Sad face. Sad face.
拍张我们的自拍
Just take a quick selfie of us.
如果我来拍就不叫自拍了 你个蠢货
It's not a selfie if I take it, you idiot.
你就乖乖拍吧 假装我是他的头部
Oh, come on. Just pretend I'm the head to his body. CLICK!
我抓住了Ricky Baker
I captured Ricky Baker!
对 你也抓住了我 你抓住了我
Yeah, you captured me too. You captured me.
我好可怜
Oh no!
好极了 兄弟 高兴点 谢谢你
Yeah. Chur, my bro. Chur. Thank you, my bro.
见到你真好 Ricky
Been awesome meeting you, Ricky.
伙计 你们继续丛林大冒险吧
Just keep doing what you're doing, man.
努力奋斗 保持野蛮本色
Keep striving. Stay Maori,
兄弟 我们需要你这样的野蛮人
bro. We need a couple more Maoris like you.
得了 闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
不 你闭嘴
No, you shut up, eh.
行了 给我出去
Yeah, get out.
我在向这位兄弟传授人生经验
I'm imparting my knowledge on the bro.
我觉得你就是个男人 你外表是男孩 但内心是个男人
You're the man for me. You're a boy, but you're a man.
兄弟 我爱你 Ricky
Bro. I love you, Ricky.
你为什么要逃走 就不能过得正常点吗
Why are you on the run? Don't you want a normal life?
不知道 也许吧
Don't know. Maybe.
你们可以过来住
You fullas could come live here.
他们永远不会找到你们的 没人会来这里
They'll never find you. Nobody ever comes in here.
我要先问问叔叔
I have to ask Uncle first.
他们说他很危险 你们处得来吗
They say he's dangerous. You guys get along?
我们就像最好的朋友 我们相处得很好
Yeah, we're like best friends. We get on so well.
他可以说 是全国最棒的丛林猎人之一
He's, like, one of the best bushmans in the whole country.
然后他 把他的本领都教给了我
He, like, teached me all of his skills,
所以现在我们 都是全国
so now we're, like, equal best
最厉害的丛林猎人 对 我们是死党
bushmen in the country. Yeah, we're best friends.
哦 那你妈妈和爸爸在哪里
Oh, where's your mum and dad?
我不知道我爸爸是谁
Don't know who my dad was,
我很小的时候我妈妈就把我抛弃了
and my mum got rid of me when I was little.
哦 那你知道她在哪吗 有没有见过她
Oh, you know where she is? You ever met her?
知不知道她是什么样的人
You know anything about her?
哟 挺漂亮的 她生下你的时候肯定还只有十几岁
Oh, pretty. She must've had you when she was a teenager.
你有没有试着去找她
You ever try and find her?
算了 你没必要去 应该是她来找你
Oh, you don't have to. She should find you.
如果你真见到她了你觉得你会说什么
What do you reckon you'd say to her if you ever met her?
不知道 我没怎么想过这个
Don't know. Never really think about it.
你想听听我写的一首歌吗
You want to hear a song I wrote?
好的 这就开始 这是我原创的
OK. Here goes. It's an original.
好吧 我说谎了 这不是我写的
OK, I lied. It's not an original.
早啊 兄弟 要香肠不
Morena, bro. Sausage?
哦不
Oh no!
对 兄弟 你留宿了
Yeah bro, you slept in.
不
Oh no!
伙计 你得好好练练下马的姿势
Man, we gotta work on your dismounts.
你从这里过得去吗
You all good from here?
可以
Yeah.
好吧 Ricky兄弟 后会有期
OK, Ricky bro, catch you up.
后会有期
Catch you up.
叔叔
Uncle!
Tupac 快来
Tupac, come on!
不
Oh no!
有忍者
Ninjas!
还有可怕的狼
Dire wolves!
是儿童福利部的人
Child Welfare!
他们去哪儿了 逃到哪里去了 你肯定有情报
Where did they go? Where did they go?! I know you know something.
他肯定知道
He knows something.
Paula 他就是那个护林员 有糖尿病 他们救了他的命
Paula, he's the ranger. He had diabetes. They saved his life.
得了吧 Andy
Oh, spare me, Andy.
这是Gavin 我们的程序员
This is Gavin, our tech guy.
Gav 我是Paula Hall 儿童福利部的 我不会放任任何一个孩子
Gav, Paula Hall, Child Welfare Services. No child left behind.
跟我说说 现在是什么情况
So, talk to me, Gav. What's the situation?
搜查结果表明 小屋是空的
Uh, well, the hut is empty
所以他们一定在我们来之前离开了这里
so they must've left before we got here.
哟 看来你已经看穿了一切 Gav
Ooh, you worked that out on your own, Gav
还有什么线索
OK, what else?
我们还在这里
Well, uh, we've, ah, set up
设立了一个搜查队的集合点
a rendezvous spot here for the search party.
这样他们就可以把黄貂鱼弄进来
And, uh, then we can bring in, uh, Stingray.
什么鱼 跟我好好说说
Stingray? Talk to me, talk to me.
简单来说就是
Oh, well, basically it's just a
一个可以发射出错误频率的便携式手机信号塔
portable cell phone tower that emits a false frequency.
周围五千米以内的手机会默认其为普通网络信号
So any cell phone in a 5 K radius will latch on,
一旦连接就可以找到位置了
thinking it's an ordinary network.
[五只眼 Five eyes 情报联盟]
棒极了 就像五只眼的那些玩意儿
Frickin' A, brother. That's some "Five eyes" Shit right there.
很好 那两个家伙马上就要被黄貂鱼了
OK. Them clowns is about to get Stingray-ed.
叔叔 叔叔 怎么找到他 冷静 好好想一想
Uncle, Uncle, Uncle. Think, think, think, think.
有了 Tupac 去找到Zag
Oh! Tupac, find Zag.
你这个没用的家伙 再想想 Rickey 好好想一想
Oh, you're useless. Oh! Think, Ricky, think.
他会做什么 叔叔他会去哪里
What would Uncle do? What would Uncle do?
有了 我知道了 去找水源 然后到高的地势上去
Oh yes. Yes! Find water, and then go to higher ground.
千万别脱光衣服
And don't get naked.
Rickey Backer 和 Hector Faulkner
Ricky Baker and Hector Faulkner-
这两个不法之徒已经逍遥法外四个月了
two renegade outlaws on the run for four months now,
迅速成为了新西兰的传奇
and fast becoming legends here in NZ.
自从上次在木屋救了护林人之后
Faulkner and Baker's popularity is on the rise
Faulkner和Baker的受欢迎程度正在火热上升
after a valiant effort to save a critically ill park ranger.
全国都在全力搜寻他们
The forces are circling against them,
这让我想起了《第一滴血》
and I am reminded of "First Blood".
John Rambo 一个人
John Rambo, a man alone- obviously they're two men alone-
不过他们是两个人
out there somewhere beyond
独自在这样野草茂密的灌木丛中生存
the cutty grass in this dense, thick bush.
看好了 就这样 简单粗暴 明白了吗
OK? Easy, efficient, economic. All right, guys?
我们来看看 当时发生了什么...
Take us back a step. What happened in...?
我有些失控 然后跟他扭打在一起
Uh, I lost control and, uh, I gave him the beating of his life.
我把他狠狠地揍了一顿
Yeah, you got him good.
我们悬赏一万元捉拿他们
We're offering $10,000 to
活要见人 死要见尸
anyone who can capture them, dead or alive.
哦 要活的 要捉活的啊
Oh,... alive. They should be alive.
他们是为自由作斗争
They are fighting for freedom.
新西兰的自由是不可侵犯的 这是一种壮举
And we believe in freedom in NZ. It is a marvellous thing.
Rickey 站住
Oi! Ricky! Freeze!
站在那儿别动我们马上过来
- OK, OK. OK, Ricky. Stay there we're coming over to you. - Come on.
这里太陡了我没法过去 Rickey 你过来
It's too steep. It's too steep. Ricky, you come across here.
我不要
No.
只需要滑下来 跨过这条小溪
Just slide down the bank, cross this stream,
然后爬上来 你会安全度过的
and then climb up to us. You're absolutely safe.
你只需要抓住一些树枝什么的就行了 好吗
All you have to do is grab some branches or some roots. OK?
我不过去
No.
Ricky 现在立刻给我过来
Ricky. Come over here right now!
我不会回去的 谁要跟你回少管所
I'm not going back. I'm not going to juvie.
小伙子 你这是在玩火
You are playing with a bag of snakes, boy.
你会引火烧身的知道不
A big bag with a lot of holes in it.
你捅了这么大的篓子 全国上下都在找你
You've got the whole country looking for you.
我不会放弃的
I'll never stop running.
我也会追你到天涯海角的
Yeah, and I'll never stop chasing you.
我会像终结者那样无情
I'm relentless. I'm like the Terminator.
我比你更像终结者
I'm more like Terminator than you.
[终结者中的角色]
我先说的 你最多就是个Sarah Conner
I said it first. You're more like Sarah Connor.
[终结者中的角色]
不 我才不是
No, I'm not.
没错 你是第一部的她 弱鸡一个
Yes. And in the first movie too, before she could do chin-ups.
我们不用搞那么多有的没的 Ricky
It doesn't have to be this difficult, Ricky. Yeah?
你又冷 又沮丧 还很饿
You're cold, you're damp... and hungry.
看看这个 混合坚果
Look at that- scroggin.
里面有坚果和一些干果
Got some nuts and dried fruit...
还有些巧克力碎 看起来就很好吃
Little pieces of chocolate. Delicious.
我们可以做个交易
We could cut a deal; make a trade.
什么交易
What kind of deal?
供出那个老家伙
The old man.
你就说是他逼你这么做的 让他来背这个黑锅
You say that he made you do it, let him take the rap,
这样我就不会把你丢到少管所去
and I'll make sure you never go back to juvie.
我们会给你找个新家 给你再找一个好妈妈
We'll find you a new foster home; a new Bella.
我拒绝
No deal.
得了吧 Sarah Conner 别做蠢事
Oh, come on, Sarah Connor. Don't be a fool.
绝不拿家人做交易
You don't trade family for anything.
好吧 那你就继续逃吧
Well, you just keep running.
他在这里 我们抓到他了
He's here! He's here. We got him!
快追
Go! Go! Go!
所以 你吃肠 她唱歌 然后你就睡了
OK. So you ate a sausage, she sang a song, and you went to sleep.
能怪我么 歌曲让人放松 香肠也让人放松
What? It was a relaxing song... and a relaxing sausage.
我们是不是走了一千英里了
Do you think we've walked
就像角马一样
a thousand miles yet? Like the wildebeest?
感觉像是走了很远是吧
Well, it feels like it, eh?
是的 一刻都不能消停 还要担心猎人们的追捕
Yeah. Always on the move, always on the lookout for hunters,
虽然我们是人类 但总是像动物一样
just like the wildebeest, except humans.
我们 我们是野蛮人
We're... Wilderpeople.
没错 就是这样
Yeah, that's us.
那好 野孩子 我们找个地方坐下来吃点东西 怎么样
OK then, Wilderboy, let's find somewhere to eat, shall we?
是他们
There they are!
别动
Freeze!
又要 动真格了
Shit just got real. Again.
丢掉你们的武器
Now, drop your weapons.
可是我们没拿着武器啊
We're not holding any weapons-
我不管 把手上的东西都扔掉
Drop 'em!
去查一下他们的东西 Ricky
Go see what they got, Ricky.
烤豆子
Baked beans,
意面
spaghetti,
这是什么鬼
ba- baba- What?
[茄子泥]
那是芭芭卡奴士
Oh, baba ganoush.
什么
What?
就是芭芭卡奴士
Baba ganoush.
怎么了
What?
望远镜
Binoculars,
绳子和胶带
rope, gaffer tape.
Ricky 把他们的枪拿过来
Get their guns, Ricky.
把你们的枪给我
Give me your guns.
把螺栓都拔掉
Take the bolts out.
有人悬赏捉拿你们
There's a reward for your capture.
赏金多少
How much?
一万
10 grand.
涨到二十万再告诉我们
Tell us when it gets to 20.
如果他们问起来是谁干的
And when they ask who did this,
告诉他们是野蛮人干的
tell them it was the Wilderpeople.
什么人
The What-er-people?
野蛮人
The Wilderpeople.
那里是Bella的农场
No, I can't go back there. It wasn't my farm;
所以我不能回去了
you know that. It was Bella's.
她管理一切
She ran the show. I could do
我只是打下手和养狗 她才是真正的农场主
stuff- me and the dog- but she was the farmer.
她还很会做饭
And the cook.
是啊 她做饭很好吃
Yeah, a bloody good cook too.
但是你不能就这么一辈子跑下去啊
But you- you can't keep on the run forever.
你需要回到社会
You've got to go back to society, you know that.
我对社会来说是个威胁
I'm a menace to society.
反正 就算回去了
Anyway, if I ever went back,
长大了最多就是个开压路机的
I'd probably end up driving a steamroller or something.
黑帮小混混通常都是这个下场
That's what happens to gangsters.
也没什么不好的啊
Well, there's nothing wrong with that,
但是如果你能在别的方面做得更好的话
but if you're better at something else,
为什么不去试试呢 对吧
then you should probably give that a go, shouldn't you?
是没错 不过我更擅长当个小混混
Yeah, but I'm better at being a gangster.
你才不是什么混混
You're not a bloody gangster.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
因为我见过真正的混混
Because I've known real gangsters,
他们比你粗鲁多了
and they're a lot tougher than you are.
他们应该很串吧
Yeah, but were they skux, though?
串 那是什么鬼
Skux? What the hell does that mean?
你懂的 就是串
You know,... skux.
到底是什么意思
Yeah, but what does it mean?
什么意思都有 很酷 很厉害的意思
Everything. It's cool, spunky,
聪明 又有型 你懂的 混混都那样
brainy, good-looking, you know, gangster.
我的老天 你真的不是混混
Oh, for God's sake. You're not a bloody gangster!
天
Oh, jeez.
Zag Tupac
Zag! Tupac!
回来 Zag 快回来
Get back, Zag! Get back! Come back here, you-!
退后 快退后 Zag
Get in behind! Get in behind, Zag!
Zag
Zag!
快点出来 你个蠢货
Get out of it, you mongrel!
该死
Shit.
叔叔
Uncle!
你都干了些什么
What have you done?
我的老天
Oh jeez.
- 把枪给我 伙计
- Give us your gun, mate.
- 快点 离开这儿 - 不 叔叔
- Go on, get out. - No, Uncle.
- 离远点 - 叔叔
- Get out of - Uncle!
- 离开这儿 Ricky 快点 走开
Get out of here, Ricky. Go on, get out.
- 但我们就不能... - 走
- But can't we just... - Go!
写的什么
What does that say?
Zag
Zag.
很好
Good.
她一路上一直跟着我们 对吗
So, she's been with us the whole time, eh?
对
Yeah.
这里离天堂很近
Well, pretty close to the sky up here.
谢谢你带着她出来 伙计
Thanks for bringing her, mate.
BGM-Leonard cohen's "The partisan"
他们打算追捕我们到什么时候啊
I wonder how long they're going to hunt us for.
难说
Oh, it's hard to say.
这些蠢货进了丛林里连你都不如
Those idiots are worse in the bush than you are.
无用至极 什么都找不到
Useless. Couldn't find a clown in a circus.
停下 警察
Stop! This is the police!
妈的
Oh shit!
什么
What?
我只是想给你说刚才那出跟里的情节一样
I was trying to tell you it was like The Lord of the Rings.
什么鬼
What the...?
你看见那棵灌木了吗
Can you see that bush over there?
看见了
Yeah.
我是人还是灌木啊
Is it a man or a bush?
灌木
Bush!
人
Man!
灌木人
Bushman!
你们好啊 我一直想和你们来次偶然的邂逅呢
Hello. I was hoping to run into you two.
如果你是冲着赏金来
Well, if you're after the reward,
那就省省力气吧 我们可是危险人物
you can bugger off. We're dangerous.
对 很危险
Yeah, we're dangerous.
是啊 不 我都听说了
Yeah, no. I heard about that.
别担心 我可没想抓你们
Don't worry. I'm not going to capture you.
你们听过一个地方传说吗
You guys heard of a- a local legend
说的是一个独自居住在这片丛林的人
about a guy who lives out here in the bush on this own?
人称神经病Sam
They call him Psycho Sam!
没有
No.
没有吗 好吧
No? Oh, OK.
总之 叫我Sam就行了
Well, my name is Sam, anyway.
我是友军 来吧
I'm a friend! Come on.
吃饼干吗
Bikkie?
他为啥叫自己神经病Sam
Why do you reckon he calls himself Psycho Sam?
给你们的 戴上这个 政府就找不到你们了
Here you go. Put these on. Stop the Government from tracking you.
当我没问
Never mind.
你们救的那个人是个护林员
That fulla you saved- he was a ranger.
有糖尿病 那事之后你们得到了点支持
Diabetic. You got a little support over that.
但不久后你们抢劫了那些赏金猎人
But then you robbed those hunters,
所以你们又陷入了麻烦里
so you're back in the negatives again.
都怪这家伙 就是个小疯子
Well, that was... this fella. He's the maniac.
他们还一直说你是个危险人物
Well, they're still saying you're dangerous.
而且有些变态
And a bit of a pervert.
去他妈的
Goddammit.
这都无所谓啦 我这里你们想住多久就住多久
It's all right. You can stay here as long as you like.
我在这待了15年了
I've been up here 15 years now.
东西齐全 他们追你们多久了
Got everything I need. How long they been chasing ya?
没算过 大概五个月吧
I don't know. About five months now?
混蛋 政府的都这德性
Bastards. That's the typical government.
总是踩在小人物头上过活
Always trying to step on the little guy just for living his life.
没完没了 所以我没法儿回去
It never stops either. That's why I can't go back.
不想成为这系统的一部分
Not going to be part of the machine.
表格填写器
Form fillers.
什么表格填写器
Form fillers?
他们就是这么折腾你的
That's how they get you.
这辈子不管你想做啥 你都得填表
Anything you want to do in life, you got to fill out a form.
他们给每件事都做了表
And they've got forms for everything.
你填一张 那张就送走了
You fill it out, it goes upstairs,
然后你又得填另一张
and then they make you fill out a new form,
就为了确认前一张是你填的
just to confirm it was you that filled out the first form.
一旦你不想填表了
And if ever you want to stop filling out forms,
很好 你再填五张不同的表来申请
well, there's about five different forms for that.
就差没拿个国家橄榄球队数目的表格出来
Don't even get me started
让我填  真是毫无人性
on the national rugby team. They're not human.
伙计 你做啥呢
What you doing, mate?
写东西
Writing.
那么Shakespeare先生 请问你在写什么大作
And what are you writing, Mr Shakespeare?
写诗
Haiku.
好吧 读来听听 我看你写得咋样
Well, go on, read it out. I'll tell you if it's any good.
不行 这是隐私
No, it's just a personal one.
行了 别扭扭捏捏的
Oh, come on. Don't be shy.
好吧
Mm, OK.
绿树 小鸟 河流 蓝天
Trees, birds, rivers, sky.
和我Hec叔叔一起逃亡
Running with my Uncle Hec.
永不分离
Living forever.
看嘛 都说了很蠢
See? Told you it was dumb.
不 没有
No, no.
只是有点
It was just that
怎么说呢 这是
Well, that's the...
这是我第一次在诗里
That's the first time I've
听见我的名字 我喜欢
heard my name in a poem. I liked it.
Bella也会喜欢这次冒险的 对吗
Gee, Bella would have loved this adventure, wouldn't she?
嗯 你俩咋不要孩子呢
Mm. Why couldn't you guys have any kids?
只是要不了
Well, just couldn't.
是我要不了
Well, I couldn't.
这不公平 有些人要不了孩子
That's not very fair. Some people can't even have babies.
而有些人有了孩子的人却不想要
And the ones who can- they don't even want them.
就像我妈一样
Like my mum.
不 小子 她想要你
No, mate. She wanted you.
她可能 她可能只是太年轻了
She was- she was probably just young.
不知道怎样养活你 明白吗
She couldn't work out how to raise you, you know.
我打赌她很爱你
I bet she loved you, though.
深表怀疑
Doubt it.
反正你永远不会知道了
Well, you never know.
你还是很讨人爱的
You're pretty likeable.
熄灯了 行吗
Lights out, OK?
晚安 Sam
Goodnight, Sam.
呃 我还没修好那灯
Oh, I haven't got that fixed yet.
晚安 叔叔
Goodnight, Uncle.
晚安 伙计
Goodnight, mate.
叔叔
Uncle!
叔叔 叔叔 叔叔 叔叔 叔叔
Uncle! Uncle! Uncle! Uncle! Uncle!
叔叔 叔叔 叔叔 叔叔 我们得走了
Uncle! Uncle! Uncle! Uncle, we have to go!
就算我受够了他的做饭水平
Yeah. Even I can't stand his cooking anymore.
我们也别一大早就说这事 行吗
We'll get out off first thing in the morning, eh?
不是 他们追来了
No! They're here.
谁
Who?
政府兵 政府兵 不好意思 借过
Government! Government! Sorry, excuse me.
他们看见你了吗
Did they see you?
没有 但他们离得很近了
No, but they're close!
快 去拿我们的东西
OK. Get our stuff!
嘿 嘿 我手机怎么回事
Hey! Hey, what happened to my phone?
我给你升级了下 现在有四格信号了
I upgraded it for ya. You're on four bars now.
你个二逼 你都干了什么
You clown. What have you done?
Faulkner先生 出来交出孩子
Come out and give over the boy, Mr Faulkner.
叔叔 叔叔 他们接近了
Uncle! Uncle! They're close.
Sam 最快离开这儿的办法是什么
Sam, what's the fastest way out of here?
喷气背包
Jet pack.
你真有喷气背包吗
Do you actually have a jet pack?
没有 怎么了
No. What?
对了 我有个地下堡垒
Wait! I've got an underground bunker.
这条隧道直通一间地下室
This tunnel leads directly to an underground chamb
我还没开挖
I haven't dug it yet. Oh!
我这辈子都在干啥
What have I been doing with my life?
完了 我们跑不掉了
That's it. We've run out of options.
装死吧 我就死在这儿
Just pretend to be dead. I'll be here.
快啊 伙计们 大家一起装才有用
Come on, guys. It only works if we all do it.
看在老天的份上 Sam 冷静一下
For Christ's sake, Sam, pull yourself together.
我们要马上离开这儿
We need to get out of here right now.
我们要怎么做
What are we gonna do?
Crumpy
Crumpy!
什么
What?
Crumpy可以带你们走
Crumpy will take you!
谁他妈是Crumpy
Who the hell is Crumpy?!
Crumpy
Crumpy!
我的天 她还启动得了吗
Jesus, does she even go?
Crumpy 活力永存 四轮驱动
Crumpy. Unkillable. Four-wheel drive.
两个轮子跑... 四轮驱动跑
Both wheels go... go four-wheel-drive.
Ricky 你到哪去了
Ricky, where are ya?
我把钥匙扔哪去了
Oh, where did I put the keys?
Ricky
Ricky!
活力永存
Unkillable!
Ricky...
上车
Get in!
Ricky Baker 你不能开这车
Ricky Baker, you are not driving this ute.
快上车
Get in the car!
见鬼
Oh shit.
Tupac
Tupac!
好了 我帮你们挡着政府兵 为你们争取些时间
OK. I'll hold up the government and buy you some time.
谢了 伙计 别干傻事
Thanks, mate. Don't do anything stupid.
我吗
Me?
你咋发动起来的
How did you get this thing started?
小技巧
The knack.
Crumpy
Crumpy!
对不住了 伙计 这车跑这路有点颠簸
Hey! Sorry, mate. She's a bit bumpy around here.
别飙车 Ricky 减速
Not too fast, Ricky. Slow down.
不 不
No! No!
树
Tree!
别挡道
Get off!
慢点
Slow down!
这是我的车
That's my bike.
闭嘴 他们是我的
Shut up, they're mine.
不如抗争到底吧 你有什么想法
May as well play it to the end. What do you reckon?
你是说我们来场枪战 然后
You mean have a shoot out, and then
等我们没子弹了 跑出去喊着 自由
when we've got no bullets, run out and say, "Freedom!"
之后死得惊天动地吗
And then die in a blaze of glory?
不 事实上我是说等我们把油耗光的时候
No. I actually meant till we run out of petrol.
哦 好吧 我要死得惊天动地了
Oh. Well, I'm dying in a blaze of glory.
别啊
No!
BGM-Moniker's "Milestone 2 "
Faulkner 我们是警察
Faulkner! This is the Police.
停车把男孩交出来
Stop the vehicle and hand over the boy.
你们几乎被包围了 无处可逃
You're pretty much surrounded. No escape.
赶紧地 伙计
Come on mate.
Faulkner先生 Faulk先生
Mr Faulkner... Mr Faulk-
快尼玛靠边停车 Faulkner
Pull the bloody vehicle over, Faulkner.
Ricky Baker
Ricky Baker!
你好啊 Paula
Hi, Paula!
你给我立刻靠边停车
You pull that ute over right now
否则你要有大麻烦了 孩子
or you're going to be in a whole lot of trouble, son!
你甚至还没拿到驾照
You don't even have your full licence!
Ricky
Ricky!
这和我想的是一回事么
Is that what I think it is?
Hec叔叔 Hec叔叔 那是货真价实的军队
Uncle Hec! Uncle Hec, that's the actual army.
这就像一场大战一样 就像 真的一样
This is like an actual war, like, for real!
收到 无线电通讯 我们看到他们了
Roger, Comms, we have visual.
Kilo Foxtrot 我们在灌木丛跟丢了
Kilo, Foxtrot. We've lost them in the bush.
可以了 停车 Ricky
OK. Stop the truck, Ricky.
- 我只是 - 停车 我现在就想下车
- I just - stop the truck. I want to get out now.
不是我选择了黑帮生活 是黑帮生活选择了我
I didn't choose the skux life; the skux life chose me.
Ricky 停下
Ricky, stop.
自由
Freedom!
我们还剩多少子弹
How many bullets do we have?
Ricky 我们得停下了
Ricky, we've got to stop.
绝不 打起精神来嘛
Never! Come on!
伙计 对我来说到此为止了 听着 我不能再逃下去了
Mate, this is it for me. Look, I can't go on anymore.
我的腿受伤了 我也几乎看不清东西
My leg is buggered. I can hardly see.
到头了
This is the end.
Ricky Baker 你给我马上从那儿出来 孩子
Ricky Baker, you get out here this instant, son.
你今天破坏了很多私人财产
You've caused a lot of damage to private property today.
你毁了这个铁皮栏杆 这不帅气 也不便宜
You've taken out this corrugated iron fence. Not cool, not cheap.
Ricky 这不是游戏 是时候就此结束了
Ricky, this isn't a game. That's real over there.
他们不会停止追捕我们的 到此为止了
They're never gonna stop chasing, ever. We're done.
我不会回去的
I'm not going back!
听着 都结束了
Listen, it's over.
叛徒
Traitor!
把枪给我 给我 喂 你 把你的枪给我
Give me your gun! Give me it! Oi, you! Give me your gun.
你的电击枪呢
Where's your taser?
被别人领走了 在惠灵顿呢
It's been booked. It's in Wellington.
关键时刻掉链子
Oh for God's sake!
刚那不是我干的
It wasn't me!
你个白痴 对枪负责这事上我是怎么教育你的
You idiot, what did I tell you about gun responsibility?
就这么定了 我要把你交出去
That's it. I'm giving you up.
我们投降
We give up!
他猥亵我
He's molestering me!
我就知道
I knew it.
你个小混蛋
You little bastard!
他是猥亵者
He's a molesterer!
我不是 他在撒谎 我不是猥亵者
I'm not! He's lying! I'm not a molesterer!
我恨透你了
I bloody hate you.
我还恨你呢 叛徒
I hate you too, traitor!
就这样 你自己玩儿去吧
That's it. You're on your own.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你再往前走一步试试
Don't you take another step.
你知道你在做什么吗
What do you think you're doing?
你知道他在干什么吗 Andy
What do you think he's doing, Andy?
Andy
Andy?
你哪儿都别想去 我们是一条船上的
You're not going anywhere. We stick together!
怎么 难不成你还会开枪打我啊
What, are you gonna shoot me?
开枪吧
Do it.
我们是一家人
We're family!
家人个大头鬼
Like hell.
来啊 开枪啊
Go ahead. Shoot me.
逮到你了 变态
Got you now, perv.
- 你居然开枪打我 - 对 对不起 对不起 这是意外
- You shot me! - I'm I'm sorry, I'm sorry! It was an accident!
我找到他了 我找到孩子了
I've got him! I've got the package!
干得好 各位
Well done, everybody!
现在我们把这个小可爱带走吧
Now let's get this precious child out of here!
对不起 叔叔 不
I'm sorry, Uncle. No!
- 谁他妈是你叔叔 - 我不是故意的
I'm not your bloody uncle. I didn't mean to!
Hector Faulkner 你被捕了
Hector Faulkner, you are under arrest.
你所说的每句话每件事
Whatever you do or say
将被作为呈堂证供
will be used against you in a court of law!
Paula
Paula!
新西兰的警察真不会这么说
Police in NZ don't really say that.
那是美国警察的台词 何况你又不是警察
That's like an American thing. And you're not a cop.
都结束了
It's over.
进去
Get in.
没错 我骑马的时候发现了他 然后我们吃了一些香肠
Yeah, I found him on my horse, and we had some sausages...
我是他的脑残粉 还跟他来了几张自拍
Uh, I'm a big fan and, uh, managed to scab me a selfie.
[电影终结者中Sarah Connor为终结者的母亲,终结者保护Sarah]
我说我是终结者他是Sarah Connor
I said that I was the Terminator and he was in fact Sarah Connor.
我说 不是我选择了黑帮生活
I said, "I didn't choose the skux life,
是黑帮生活选择了我
uh, the skux life chose me."
谁将抚养他 有没有可能...
Who is going to give him that upbringing? Is it perhaps...?
我们只是想要给孩子最好的 尊敬的法官阁下
We just want what's best for the child, Your Honour.
掠 掠夺
"Mara- Mara-u-ding
和抢劫 …
"And plunder... ing the
宇… 宙…
"Uni... univer... universe...
养... 育...
"Rising... up..."
Ca caw …aga
Ca-caw! "... aga-"
Ca caw Hec
Ca-caw, Hec!
嗨
Hi.
监狱生活怎么样 有和人干架吗
How was jail? Did you shank anyone?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉我开枪打了你
I'm sorry that I shot you,...
还有很抱歉我烧了你的棚屋
and I'm sorry that I burnt down your shed.
够了
That's enough.
以及对我那天说的话道歉
And I'm sorry for what I said that day,
关于说你是猥亵者的话
about you being a molesterer.
真的够了 我快受不了了
That really is enough; I'm getting uncomfortable.
我只是沉迷于当逃犯 太好玩了
I just got carried away being an outlaw; had too much fun.
过得还好吗
Been doing all right?
还好 我得被困在新的家庭里
Yeah, I just had to stick it out
整整一年 我做到了 你会喜欢他们的
in a new family for a year. I did. You'll like them.
你会喜欢那儿的 那里有很多房间
Man, you'd love it there. There's heaps of room,
他们的农场需要帮手
they need some help on the farm,
就在灌木丛边上
it's right next to the bush...
噢 我还攒钱买了这个
Oh, and I also saved up and got this.
你想找到那只鸟
You want to find that bird?
是啊 我们会出名的
Yeah. We'll be famous.
你最好别带上我 伙计
Nah, you're better off without me, mate.
是啊 但是我...
Yeah. But I...
我只是想
I just thought that...
好吧
Ok.
对不起
Sorry.
嘿 等等
Hey. Wait on.
我有些话想说
I've got something to say.
我和这个小胖墩
Me and this fat kid-
一起逃亡 一起觅食 一起读书
We ran, we ate, and read books.
那是段美好的时光
And it was the best.
It was the best.
是啊
Yeah.
听着 说实话
Look, to tell you the truth,
我待不下去了 这里都是一帮老家伙
I can't stand it here. It's full of old people.
所以 你要一起去吗
So... you're coming?
是啊 是的 我也一起去 不能让你这种小混蛋
Yeah. Yeah, I'm coming. Wouldn't want a little twerp like you
独吞了找鸟的功劳
to get all the credit for finding a bird.
行 但是我有一个条件
Yeah, but I've got one rule-
你得让我叫你叔叔
you got to let me call you "Uncle".
叔叔
Uncle?
好吧 我可以接受
Yeah, I can stand that.
我也有一个条件
I've got one rule too.
不许朝我开枪
Not allowed to shoot me.
好 我要... 我要去拿牙刷
OK, I'll... I'll go and get my toothbrush.
要出发了 觉得你能应付的了吗
Here we go. Reckon you can handle it?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
觉得你能找到那只鸟吗
Reckon you can find that bird?
可以 我想我知道它在哪
Yeah. I think I know where it is.
记得这是个挺漂亮的地方 是吧
Seem to remember it was a pretty beautiful place, was it?
是啊 壮观
Yeah. Majestical.
来吧 我们走吧
Come on. Let's go.
别拖我后腿 老家伙
Don't slow me down, old fulla.
你自己别掉队了 年轻人
Keep up yourself, young player.
别当我的道 不然对你不客气了
Get in my way, I'll have your guts for garters.
老实说我不知道"不客气了"是什么意思 所以...
Well, I honestly don't know what "Guts for garters" Is, so...
这是黑帮的行话
Well, it's gangster talk.
是啊 不是我们选择了黑帮生活...
Yeah. We didn't chose the skux life...
是黑帮生活选择了我们
... the skux life chose us.
是啊
Yeah.
BGM-Alessi brothers' "Seabird"
支持我们，欢迎购买VIP移除所有广告，具体：www.OpenSubtitles.org